# Mohamed Moustafa

### Software Engineer

(updated at resume.fairewinds.ca)

https://fairewinds.ca

<u>mti.moustafa@gmail.com</u>

🌎 GitHub: <u>@mtimoustafa</u>

in LinkedIn: <u>@mtimoustafa</u>

Twitter: <u>@mtimoustafa</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm a full-stack software engineer with 7 years of experience in SaaS-based platforms. I specialize in design systems and web accessibility. I also have experience leading projects and cross-team initiatives. In my free time I play music, read, and work on coding projects.

**SKILLS** 

UI frameworks

Design systems

WCAG 2.0/2.1
acessibility

Microservice
API design and
Containerised
development

deployment

Javascript / Vue.js

Ruby / Ruby on Rails

HTML / CSS / SCSS

**TECH STACK** 

Docker / Kubernetes MySQL / PostgreSQL AWS

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### SENIOR BACK-END ENGINEER

MARCH 2022 - CURRENT

#### Livestorm

Paris, France (Remote)

- Worked with Infrastructure team to set up new "Job Manager" microservice using AWS, Kubernetes, and Terraform.
- Maintained, refactored, and documented public-facing API layers in a crossdiscipline (design, product, development) team setting, using Ruby on Rails and Swagger.
- Implemented new features for the application dashboard UI, using Vue.js, GraphQL and Apollo.

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

AUGUST 2021 - FEBRUARY 2022

**Springest (now Studytube)** Amsterdam, Netherlands

- Led research and construction of a proof-of-concept for containerizing a monolithic application into Docker.
- Implemented and maintained core features with a full-stack scope in Ruby on Rails and Vue.js.
- Acted as a mentor for a project to refactor core "Course Listing" back-end model design.

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

**APRIL 2017 - JULY 2021** 

#### Vidyard

Kitchener, Ontario, Canada

- Helped implement and maintain internal design system using Vue.js. The design system is used across all front-end services in the platform.
- Guild lead of internal design system. The guild (working group) consisted of 6+ engineers, designers, and QAs, and governed future goals and maintainership.
- Maintainer of key platform services, primarily using Ruby on Rails and Vue.js.
   Responsible for code reviews, refactoring and bugfixing, deploys, and mentorship.
- Responsible for upgrading major and most-trafficked parts of the platform to WCAG AA 2.0 accessibility standards.
- Mentored co-workers on how to develop for accessibility in a technical and design capacity.
- Led a project to create a new search feature. Refactored RESTful API endpoints and improved the existing ElasticSearch implementation.
- Refactored a stand-alone microservice to use Docker, Kubernetes, Skaffold, and OAuth, in order to integrate it into our development environment.
- Improved Vidyard Chrome Extension features and UI, using React.js.

Full work experience available on LinkedIn

#### **EDUCATION**

### UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

2011 - 2016

Waterloo, Ontario, Canada

BASc. with Honours, Computer Engineering, Co-operative (Internship) Program

Relevant Courses

- Operating Systems and Systems Programming
- Cooperative and Adaptive Algorithms
- Fundamentals of Computational Intelligence

#### CONFERENCES

- VueConf Toronto (2019, 2020)
- #a11yTO Accessibility Toronto (2019)
- University of Guelph Accessibility Conference (2018, 2019)

#### **INTERESTS**

#### **LANGUAGES**

EnglishArabicGermanDutch(native)(learning)(learning)

#### **INTERESTS**

- Former member of diversity+inclusion & wellness committees.
- Former volunteer at community initiatives in Ontario, Canada.
- I build and maintain small coding projects, including a sync tool between financial tools, running Minecraft in Docker, and a crochet project tracker.
- I play the guitar, bass and piano & experiment with music production.
- I like to read sci-fi and personal development books.